Contact

anastasia.schmidt88@gmail.c

www.linkedin.com/in/anastasia-schmidt-94729b30 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Critical Care

NICU

Nursing

Languages

English

Certifications

CCRN

ECMO Specialist, CES-A

Honors-Awards

Saint Louis Magazine Excellence in Nursing, Cardiovascular winner

Anastasia Schmidt

Assistant nurse manager, Cardiothoracic ICU, Barnes Jewish Hospital

Greater St. Louis Area

Summary

Skilled ICU nurse with diverse experience in caring for critically ill patients, ranging from neonates to geriatrics, including neonatal, pediatric and adult ECMO expertise. Career goals include expanding critical care knowledge wherever possible to give the best care to the sickest patients.

Experience

Barnes-Jewish Hospital 3 years 1 month

Assistant Nurse Manager, Cardiothoracic ICU January 2020 - Present (7 months)

Greater St. Louis Area

RN, Cardiothoracic ICU

July 2017 - December 2019 (2 years 6 months)

- -Nursing management of critically ill adults with diagnoses ranging from postoperative cardiac surgery, cardiogenic shock, heart failure, heart and lung transplant, thoracic surgery, vascular surgery and more
- -Charge nurse in 56CTICU and 83CTICU
- -Special skills include epicardial pacemakers, CVVHD/SLED, ECMO, Impella, intra-aortic balloon pumps, Heartmate and Heartware ventricular assist devices, vasoactive and inotropic medication titration, and chest tube management and removal.
- -EPIC super user for hospital-wide transition from COMPASS to EPIC electronic charting system
- -Family- and patient-centered care throughout the ICU process as well as support to families and patients at end of life
- -Super-user for hospital-wide CLABSI prevention effort

St. Louis Children's Hospital
Pediatric Advanced ECLS Specialist
January 2019 - January 2020 (1 year 1 month)

St. Louis Children's Hospital
Registered Nurse
January 2012 - July 2017 (5 years 7 months)
Saint Louis, Missouri

- -Nursing management and assessment of critically ill neonates and infants in a large level IV NICU, as well as critically ill ECMO patients in PICU and Pediatric Cardiac ICU from ages 0-19, and support of families in crisis -Perform duties as pod charge and resource charge nurse including making pod assignments, assessing staffing levels and admission plans, acting a unit resource, and carrying unit code pager with responsibilities to attend codes -Member of NICU Transport Team, responsible for delivery room stabilization and safe transport of premature and critically ill infants requiring a higher level of care from Barnes-Jewish Hospital to St Louis Children's Hospital -Member of SLCH ECMO team, September 2015-present. Duties include managing VA and VV ECMO using protocols and algorithms in a multidisciplinary team for patients in the NICU, PICU and Cardiac ICU with over 1200 pump hours
- -Preceptor of new ECMO specialists in NICU, PICU and Cardiac ICU -Support of families during end-of-life situations in NICU, PICU and Cardiac ICU

Memorial Medical Center, Springfield IL Registered Nurse July 2011 - December 2011 (6 months)

-Experienced in detailed assessments and medicine administration to both oncology patients and medical/surgical patients, including heparin drips, blood and platelet

administration and antineoplastic materials excluding chemotherapy

- -Experience in maintenance of PICC lines, infus-a-port systems, Ash and Hohn catheters, as well as peripheral lines, and dressing changes for all of the above.
- -Participation in graduate nurse residency education program

Missouri Baptist Medical Center
Unit Secretary, Patient Care Tech
March 2009 - June 2011 (2 years 4 months)
Mother/Baby, Labor and Delivery, Newborn nursery

-Responsible for patient charts, admissions, discharges, and entering orders and

lab work

- -Responsible for care of up to 42 newborns in newborn nursery
- -Responsible for feedings, vital signs, assisting in circumcisions and appropriate documentation
- -Responsible for capillary lab draws and transcutatenous bilirubin monitoring

Education

Saint Louis University
BSN, Nursing · (2007 - 2011)

Kirkwood High School · (2003 - 2007)